你 AI 是展示人体强大的恢复力的实例
You, Al, are an object lesson in the healing powers of obstinacy...
也是战胜病魔的典型
and a hostile disposition.
我仍然四肢无力
My leg and arm are waxy.
你对它们感觉如何并不重要
How they feel to you is not the relevant measure.
我会依据他们对刺激的反应进行实际的判断
I judge objectively the way they respond to stimuli...
它们好多了
and they are much fucking improved.
总体来讲  先生  我称之为奇迹
In the overall, sir, I call you a miracle.
准备觐见吧
Ready to meet the world.
沃尔科特先生 你希望我买债权这事再干多长时间
How much longer you suppose I'll be buying claims, Mr Wolcott?
快完事了
We're close to the end.
再不完事  我就要穷得穿内裤在这跳舞了
Otherwise, I'll need to start dancing out here in long johns...
而不是像现在这样抱怨了
or baying at the moon.
也会透漏给人们我要逆势而为的信息了
Give people some idea of why I'm going against logic.
这个阶段要结束了
This phase is nearly over...
同时另一阶段将要开始
even as another begins.
我提出建立银行的计划
I propose formation of a bank...
斯塔尔先生  你任执行官
Mr Star, with yourself as chief officer...
我在营地的财产做抵押
my holdings in the camp standing surety...
埃尔斯沃斯先生担任我的股份的监管人
and Mr Ellsworth as overseer of my interests.
我明白
I see.
可惜我没做个振奋人心的发言
Not quite a rousing endorsement.
盖勒特夫人  那就不必了
It's just what's needed, Mrs Garret.
我不知道我该不该参与
I don't know that I should be part of it.
为什么呢  斯塔尔先生？
Why, Mr Star?
我有其他的义务在身
Other obligations.
你
Oughtn't you...
或者其他任何想利用人情限制你资格的人
or anyone urging such connections as disqualifying you...
就不考虑一下营地给我们带来的好处么？
think of the good of the camp?
我们都有
We all have...
复杂的义务
complicating obligations.
这些会是我的新员工么？
Might those be my new employees?
两虎之间必有一争啊
There's a combat in prospect between those two.
就好比苏族和白人
As equal as the Sioux with the Whites.
怎么样？
All right?
Well  你左边高大约半头
Well, you left upright, about half a cunt hair.
Well  那就把我扶正了
Well, bring me fucking straight then.
我给他弄吧  丹
I got him, Dan.
Whoa.
对了  就这样  笔直
Right, there you go. Straight as a string.
退后吧  约翰尼
Stand back then, Johnny.
有口水流下来么  有血点么
Any drool, first fucking fleck,
你按住我的时候留下的？
you give me this.
你从来就没流过口水  艾尔
You never showed no fucking spittle, Al.
要按我说的做哦
Do as I fucking say.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
我进去
I'm going in.
那为啥是我坐在最前排呢？
Then why am I in first chair?
你们能给他口交么？
Anyone else suck his prick?
托利维先生  你抛弃了我
You washed your hands of me, Mr Tolliver...
当我被暴民包围的时候
when I was beset amid that rabble...
卑鄙可比本丢・彼拉多(钉死耶稣的罗马犹太总督)
no less contemptibly than Pontius Pilate.
有时候影子是保护之手投下的
Sometimes the shadow's cast by the sheltering hand.
你是说暴民在你的控制之下？
Meaning the rabble was under your control?
不是  先生  我控制不了他们
No, sir. Wouldn't have them.
但我刚才是以他们的方式思考的
I am attuned, though, to the workings of what passes for their minds.
早上我们已经看到结果了
This morning we see the result:
更多的债权被抛售  价格更低了
more claims offered for sale and prices pressed downward.
拥有者害怕你把怒火倾泻在他们头上
You suppose the owners fear you might visit your ire on their titles?
-我想离开这里  -我理解
-I want to get out of here. -I understand.
你离开前会有点闲暇么？
Will you have a quick wind of your timepiece before you go?
没有  先生  我没功夫了
No. No, sir, I will not.
我感到脚下的土壤正在被水冲走
I feel the earth washing away from beneath me.
我想离开
I want to go away.
我们会想你的
We'll fucking miss you.
还有你  沃尔科特先生
And you, Mr Wolcott,
我发现你是最让人失望的
I find you the most severe disappointment of all.
我对自己也经常如此
Often to myself as well.
我们预料他会给杨克顿带去什么样的印象呢？
What impressions do we expect he'll take to Yankton?
你的钱花在了那儿
That your money spends...
所以我会是个但杨克顿不认为是的危险分子
and I'm a dangerous man with whom to disagree.
你把我们组在一起
You put us together,
不会让我们给赫斯特先生留下坏印象
don't that make us the very image of Mr Hearst...
因为他想让杨克顿考虑他
as he'd want Yankton to think of him?
你家的那个犹太人怎么样？
How's the Jew-fucking going?
还行
It's all right.
这个信息对我有什么帮助？
What does it add to my understanding?
今早他去见那个寡妇了
He's meeting with the widow this morning.
他和另一个人提到了建银行 这件事上也提到了她
Spoke to the other of forming a bank, and of her in that connection.
-你说的另一个人是谁？  -布洛克
-Who's the fucking "other"? -Fucking Bullock.
我的情感没那么娇气
My sensibilities do not need coddling, either.
与你无关
It's no concern for you.
我不想叫出那个混蛋的名字
I don't like naming the cocksucker.
不管怎样  那可能就是打算了
Anyways, that may be its purpose...
他和那个寡妇坐在一起
he‘s sitting down with the widow.
那个犹太人？
The Jew?
我希望你能为和他滚床单收点钱
I hope you're getting paid for the pussy.
你不定价就会失去他们的尊重
Don't put a price to it, you'll lose their respect.
他教我算账了
He's teaching me accounts.
那就没事了
That's all right then.
对他们来说学习就是货币了
Learning is like currency to them.
他和我做爱是看着我的眼睛  赤裸裸的渴望
He stares in my eyes when he fucks me, longing-like.
上帝啊
Jesus Christ.
你看起来不太糟
You don't look so bad.
Yeah  下一件事呈上来
Yeah, next thing to up and about.
夫人  我可以打扰一下么？
Ma'am, may l?
A・W・梅里克  夫人  黑山先锋报
A.W. Merrick, ma'am, of the Black Hills Pioneer...
冒昧的介绍下自己
making bold to introduce himself.
我是玛丽・斯托克斯  梅里克先生
I am Mary Stokes, Mr Merrick.
我想是的 果然如此  认识你很高兴  夫人
I thought so! I hoped so. I'm delighted to make your acquaintance, ma'am.
也替你要教的营地孩子们高兴
And for the camp's children, whom you will edify.
-这是你的么？ -是的
-ls this yours? -Yes.
还有你的包  你的包 我们看看是不是在上面
And your bags, your bags. Let's see, are they up here?
别说实话
Liar.
-崔克茜小姐  -怎么了？
-Miss Trixie. -What is this now?
没什么糟糕的事  我在找你
Nothing nefarious. I was looking for you.
我被震惊了
My nerves have had a shock.
-怎么了？ -盖勒特夫人情况不怎么好
-How so? -Mrs Garret took poorly.
在会见斯塔尔先生的时候？
At the meeting with Mr Star?
过来谈
Come here.
我补充点
I'll add that...
最近几周她都不怎么好
she hasn't looked well the last few weeks...
尤其早上  眼色苍白
especially in the morning. Pale.
你在暗示什么？
What are you fucking hinting at?
－什么也没有  －没事？
-Nothing. -Nothing?
她就早上脸色苍白  其他时间不这样么？
She ain't looked well mornings opposed to the rest of the day? Pale?
怎么我说出我的发现反而受指责了？
How does sharing observations make me liable to rebuke?
换句话说  你让她怀孕了
You got her knocked up, in other words.
我？ 我不会让她怀孕的  崔克茜
Me? I ain't got her in any way at all, Trixie.
在你看来  我在讲的  就是她怀孕了
In your opinion, I'm saying, she's in the way.
我受雇佣而为她工作
I work for the woman in her fucking employ.
我理解
I understand that.
那就是全部了
And that is the sole fucking full extent of it.
你想做对的事么？
Would you do the right thing?
此事与我无关啊
I was not involved.
我们跳过这个  我知道与你无关
We're fucking past that. I know you weren't fucking involved.
那与谁有关呢？
Who was involved, too...
就事态发展来看？
far as that fucking goes?
你愿意么？
Would you?
我愿意什么？
Would I fucking what?
在这个情形下干点对的事
Do the right fucking thing in that fucking situation?
什么情形？解释一下啊
What's the situation? Explain it.
如果她想要这个孩子
If she wanted the child...
一个女人是多么想要一个孩子
how a woman wants one
而且不确定她能够忍受许多
that ain't certain she's made to bear many...
她甚至愿意忍受未婚生子
willing even to bear it out of wedlock...
承受伤害  承受屈辱
but for the hurt she'd do another and the humiliation she'd do...
还会对另一个女人的孩子造成这些影响
and to that other woman's little boy.
那么你愿意吗？
Would you do it then?
愿意？
Do?
做正确的事  别惺惺作态
The right fucking thing. Don't get fucking coy with me.
你是说娶她？
Marry her, you're saying?
在他人看来孩子
And the child in the eyes of others...
就是我的了
the issue of my loins.
他们只关心表面
As much as they care to see.
这只会暂时的吸引大家的眼球
This is only a passing glance.
而精液又不是当着他们的面射出来
So the cum's true author ain't thrown in their fucking face.
或者是肇事者妻子的面
Or the true author's wife's face,
又或者是当着那个小孩的面
or the face of that little fucking boy.
Well?
她愿意我娶她么？
Would she fucking have me?
我去解决这事
I'd work on that next.
-课本  -Oh  漂亮
-Books. -Ah, wonderful.
我在俾斯麦群岛把它们分装在几个箱子里了
I parted with several boxes in Bismarck.
我支持俾斯麦改革
I'm sure to Bismarck's betterment.
大部分缘由是为了孩子们
Mostly for the sake of the children.
那我猜其他的缘由
The other few, might I suspect...
就是因为你自己的某种儿时记忆了
for the sake of certain childhood memories of your own?
你可能是猜对了
You may, and be in the right.
斯托克斯夫人  你去住处的时候
When you're situated, Miss Stokes...
我可以陪你参观营地么？
may I take you on a tour of the camp?
那我就谢了
I would be grateful.
斯托克斯夫人  包在我身上了
no more than l, Miss Stokes, I assure you.
Oh  一个男的来到了营地  沃尔科特
Oh, a man's come to camp. Wolcott.
代理赫斯特的利益
Agent for the Hearst's interest.
我相信他和杨克顿还有托利维通过话
I believe he's made calls with Tolliver and Yankton.
那就是为什么杨克顿突然有胆量了
That's why Yankton's suddenly got balls.
我让他错以为我要骗他
I made him think I was trying to gull him...
但他反而逆转了
and that he had turned the tables on me.
他花了多少钱收买你？
How much did he buy you for?
你恢复中的时候我让丹上报了
I kept Dan apprised while you convalesced...
以简短的形式
in abbreviated fashion.
多少钱？
How much?
Oh  1万美金
Oh, $10,000.
他认为  招募我  来传播债权失效的谣言
Enlisting me, so he thought, to spread rumours about rescission of the claims.
托利维出头？
Tolliver's the front?
从恐慌的卖者手里买  被沃尔科特雇佣
Buying from the panicked sellers, engaged by this Wolcott.
代理乔治・赫斯特？
This agent for George Hearst?
简而言之就是如此
That's it in a nutshell.
AI  我没对你不忠
I meant you no disloyalty, Al.
你为自己打算以防我死了
You look out for yourself against the chance I'd die.
我绝对没希望是那个结果
I never wished for that outcome.
但我是天生的追随者
But I am a born follower.
无论如何  现在是我们在一起了
In any case, here we are...
如果战术上不利  那就要从力量上补回来了
if tactically disadvantaged, exactly as before in strength.
Oh  当然  谢谢接见  先生
Oh, sure. Thank you, sir.
-早上好  -早上好  索尔
-Morning. -Morning, Sol.
谢谢帮我开张
Thanks for opening.
你出去了
You were out.
是的  我出门拜访然后走了一会儿
Yes. Yes, I paid a call and then I've been walking.
拜访的是盖勒特夫人
The call was on Mrs Garret.
我们说好不这么干的
We agreed that wasn't gonna happen.
我们的协议是不请她投资银行
Our agreement was to not solicit her investment in a bank.
这次拜访是应她邀请的
The call I paid was at her invitation.
我不在乎谁邀请谁  索尔
I don't give a fuck who invited who, Sol.
那是你的立场
That's your position.
银行是会议的议题么？  出去
Was the bank the subject of the meeting? Get out!
请等我们一会儿
Excuse us a little while, please.
她邀请的我  塞斯
She invited me, Seth.
讨论成立银行  来这儿邀请你么？
To talk of forming a bank, came here and invited you?
派来了为她工作的埃尔斯沃斯
Sent Ellsworth that works for her.
你没告诉我这事
You told me none of it.
怕你表现得不理智
Suspecting maybe you mightn't act rational.
但我肯定你告诉那个妓女了
But I bet you told the whore.
这事我们现在谈完了
We're done talking about this for now.
-没有  -谈完了  塞斯
-No! -Yes, Seth.
我们已经谈完这事了
We're done talking about this.
如果你坚持  咱俩就得打架了
If you keep it up, we're going to fight...
然后我调养期间你就得自己工作了
and you'll have to work by yourself while I convalesce.
斯维尔根先生  我被艾尔玛・盖勒特雇佣到深夜
Until late, Mr Swearengen, I was employed by Alma Garret...
作为她监护的孤儿的教师
as tutor to her orphan ward.
-两天前被解雇  -让她说
-Sacked two days ago. -Let her tell it.
在我被雇佣期间
In the course of my employment...
我经常看到盖勒特夫人处于鸦片的影响下
I frequently saw Mrs Garret under the influence of opiates.
在此状态  她对我承认
In this state, she admitted to me...
她委托别人做得她丈夫的谋杀案
having commissioned the murder of her husband.
多么荒唐的世界啊
What a world.
她说你是她的行凶者
She named you as her instrument.
说我杀了他？
Said I killed him?
她没详细说你真得杀了他
She never specified you'd actually killed him.
-说得很模糊  -不错
-Left it vague-like. -Exactly.
-我是行凶者？ -是的
-That I was her instrument? -Yes.
那我们就能说成是别人
So we could pin it on someone else,
否则我就得代人受罪 供认
or I could take the fall, confess...
-支持你的说法  -是的
-supporting your version -Yes.
写下来  然后逃跑
In writing and then subsequently escape.
这是已知中将会发生的
Such has been known to occur.
留下寡妇一个人在牢房里
Leaving the widow lonely at the bar of justice.
总比一个都没有强
Better one than none at all.
-你为谁卖命？  -卑鄙的人
-Who do you work for? -People of means.
你为之工作的人是被卑鄙的人雇佣的
People you work for were hired by people of means.
不用小心翼翼地  伊斯林豪瑟小姐
Don't get cagey, Miss lsringhausen.
我提醒下  斯维尔根先生
Let me suggest, Mr Swearengen...
你还没偏离自己的机会
you do not get distracted from your opportunity.
你不应考虑我为谁工作  而是你要付多少钱
Not who I work for should concern you, but the amount you'll be paid...
以及接款人的担保
and the surety of its delivery.
太他妈对了
Too fucking true.
为什么我真想祈祷不是平克顿呢  他们收买了你
Why, I pray fervently it ain't the Pinkertons whose pay you're in...
她丈夫的家人雇佣了他们来偷她的金子
and that her dead husband's people hired to steal her gold.
我没缘由的讨厌那些混蛋
I got unrelated reasons to hate those cocksuckers.
5万美元
$50,000.
我想不出来其他可能的人会是谁
I'm hard-pressed to think who the fuck else it would be.
5万美元  斯维尔根先生
$50,000, Mr Swearengen.
从你付给你下属的钱里出
Separate from pay to your subordinates.
从你的口袋 不是我的[说给塞拉斯的]
Your pockets, not mine?
是的
Yes.
需要为他和你做爱付钱么？
Would it go against his for the pussy?
不必为滚床单付款
No charge for the pussy.
-介意我考虑一天么？ -不介意
-Mind if I take the day? -Not at all.
眼下我还有很多事要做
I've got a lot on my plate just now...
并且我感觉还没到让我筋疲力尽的程度
and I'm feeling less than my full fucking self.
你让我感到害怕
You seem quite formidable to me.
不管怎样我等着从塞拉斯那儿听信儿
In any case, I'll wait to hear from Silas.
成交
Do.
这是很大一笔钱啊
That'd be grand.
我感觉我要是骂你妓女  我感觉你都不会晕倒
I guess if I called you a cunt, I needn't expect you to faint?
-是的  -乍一听到会有点受打击么？
-No. -Getting struck be a first?
我怎么损害你的利益了？
How have I injured your interests?
做梦他在楼上正考虑给我升职？
Think he's upstairs considering me for promotion?
无论如何  离开我的房间
Anyway, clear out of my room.
过来干我吧  为什么不呢？
Come up and fuck me, why don't you?
这么简单？  我害怕被蛇咬
Simple as that? I'd fear a snakebite.
上来干我  我会回答你问的每一个问题
Come up and fuck me, and I'll answer every one you want to ask.
早上好  治安官
Morning, Sheriff.
你足够冷静地听我说话了么？
You sober enough to listen?
你想羞辱我？
Did you just intend to insult me?
-抱歉  治安官 -我知道
-Excuse me, Sheriff. -I know.
你面子被撅了
You face business reverses.
就好像正在失去的债权
Like losing my fucking claim.
为困难生气的人往往表现得像个白痴
People angry at their difficulties often act like fucking idiots...
但是也不能谋杀这个营地的任何肤色的人
but there'll be no murdering people in this camp of any colour...
或者袭击任何类别的政府官员
or assaults on officials of any stripe.
即使杨克顿那些和上帝勾结的贼都知道阴谁？
Even Yankton thieves who are in league with God knows fucking who?
官员来自于杨克顿或者其他方面  是或不是贼
Officials from Yankton or otherwise, or thieves or not.
如果你受不了就离开这个营地
If you can't live with that, get out of this fucking camp.
我能受得了  但你就得给我收拾烂摊子了
I can live with it. You have to keep rubbing my fucking nose in it?
不要再在营地撒野
Do not misconduct yourself again in this camp.
他必须得按治安官说得做么？
Must he take what the Sheriff just fucking give him?
明显是啊
Apparently so.
他没必要的  这儿没有惯例  没有法律
He needn't. Not by custom, not by fucking law.
给我指条道吧
Name my remedy then.
地上每个政府所在之外都有照顾不到的地方
Outside every county courthouse in the land is the lady blindfolded.
不错  目前来讲的确如此
True, far as it goes.
别拿他们当回事就能平衡了
To ignore how them scales she carries sometimes gets balanced out.
在政府里  我没有地位
There, I take no position.
我可以弄个皮头
I could take a leather punch...
捅进那个混蛋的马屁股
and stab the bastard's horse in the fucking ass.
你可以的  那就对了
You could, and you'd be in the right.
在它身上刻上写上：布洛克  我干了你的马
Carve on its coat: "Bullock, I fucked your horse..."
咱们的帐抵消了
and square the fucking scales.
如果摘下眼罩  看到那个女士在眨眼
And if the blindfold was down, see the lady a-winking...
然后她告诉你  你干的真像个男人
while she told you, you done it like a man.
如果我刻上‘干’  那么我会
And if I carve "fuck," I will...
去对着唱诗班说吧
Preaching to the choir.
-多谢  -没事
-Thanks. -Sure.
可能会沾上点屎的
Mingle the shit somewhat.
你应该少说两句
You ought to take up whittling.
船长  准备收钱吧  交换所有权
Ready to receive currency, Captain, in exchange for titles.
好的
Yes.
因为我做的维持演说  所以记功时…
And as I've learned to sustain discourse while counting...
我想和你商量一下
I'm gonna ask you to take counsel with me.
关于什么？
In what regard?
首先  我们要达成一致  中国妓女卖相不好
Well, first, let's agree them Chink whores make a poor appearance.
是的
Yes.
就她们关押的地方而言  她们不吸引人
And as far as locales for fucking them cribs they're in lack allure.
她们可以吸引有意的客户
They might attract the intended clientele.
现在  有个想法我想让我们商量一下的
Now, that's an attitude right there I want us to counsel on.
自作聪明的那种想法
Smart-alecky sort of attitude...
可能会有点气人
and almost with a quality of fucking anger to it.
我找不到一个准确的词来描述
I don't find exact fucking words for it...
但是它让我烦扰、担心
but it fucking disturbs and concerns me.
在我看来  我感觉我安排的挺好
By my lights, I feel I manage well.
Well  沃尔科特先生  你当然可以那么说
Well, you can say that, Mr Wolcott...
然而我听到的描述是
yet I hear accounts...
你是个危险的嫖客
that you're a dangerous lay...
这加深了我的烦扰
and that adds to my feeling disturbed.
你有点偏心  先生 偶尔
Are you inclined, sir, every so often...
要把人挤下悬崖
to ride one off the cliff?
姑娘们  我是说？
Girls, I mean?
我的私人生活被提及让我很是不安
I am disturbed at my private conduct being spoken of.
Well   我应该想到你会如此的
Well, I should think you fucking would be.
应该先考虑赫斯特先生的不安
And to think of Mr Hearst's disturbance
如果赫斯特先生知道的话
if he was to fucking know.
因为
Because...
当你不在朋友之间时  放纵是个危险的习惯
that's a dangerous habit to indulge when you're not among friends.
你是我的朋友么  托利维先生？
Are you my friend, Mr Tolliver?
有些人经过对于习惯 偏袒 形势变化的惊讶
And someone past surprise at habits or inclination, or turns of events...
就不会困扰自己了  直到和基督
and who don't confuse himself far as sitting in judgement...
一起坐在天堂评判他人
with our Lord in fucking Heaven.
-我明白  -那么
-I see.  -And...
不会泄露给你的老板的人也不会
who would never tattle to your employer...
危及自己快要到手的可观的收入
or jeopardise what's got to be a handsome fucking income.
他妈的 对了  我是你的朋友  沃尔科特先生
Goddamn right, I am your friend, Mr Wolcott.
我唯一不能提供会给这次联合的就是绝路
All I can't provide for the party is the cliff.
你要相信刚发生的惊讶是不会让你变成我的朋友的
Believing yourself past surprise does not commend you to me as a friend.
一个不够世故
A man inadequately sophisticated...
并且有点愚昧  还有点愚蠢的男人
or merely ignorant, or simply stupid...
可能会相信这个惊讶结束了
may believe himself past surprise...
然后会惊讶的发现  比如
then be surprised to discover, for example...
赫斯特先生已经知道并且意识到了我的偏心
that Mr Hearst already knows of my inclinations and finds them immaterial.
我的建议  作为结论  你敲诈和操纵的技巧
Suggesting, as a corollary, that your skills for blackmail and manipulation...
不再是你拥有的财富了
no longer are assets to you...
对于你那愚蠢的准则  在使用的效果上
and for your fatuous belief in their efficacy...
事实上  已经变成了债务
in fact, have become liabilities.
简而言之  你手伸过界了
In short, you've overplayed your hand.
现在  我因此认为
Now, I should think in consequence...
察觉了你是一个在最后的过渡时期
now recognising yourself as a man past his time...
错过了自己时机的人
that during this last transitional period...
你最好感激、勤勉的奉献自己
you would devote yourself with grateful and quiet diligence...
到这些用处上  因为有人发现你仍然适合干这些事
to such uses as others may still find you suitable.
你赌我会感激涕零  一个像你这样的人
Oh, you bet I'm grateful. A man like yourself...
靠在赫斯特先生怀里
warmed at Mr Hearst's bosom...
用他的信任获得保障
secure in his confidence and trust...
花着时间和精力来说服像我这么顽固的人
taking the time and spending the energy to persuade a relic like me.
她在芝加哥 波士顿 纽约登广告找家教
She'd placed adverts for a tutor in Chicago, Boston and New York.
薪酬驱使我来看看
The interests that employ me saw.
-那时你在做什么？  -开汽船
-What was you doing at the time? -Piloting a steamboat.
对于雇你阴她的人 AI说得对么？
Was Al right who hired you people to fuck her up?
我也没被告知
That's not something I'm told.
肯定是她死去的丈夫的家人
Must be the dead husband's parents...
如果他们想吊死她的话
if they want to hang that murder off her neck.
有可能
That would make sense.
为什么斯维尔根讨厌平克顿呢？
Why does Swearengen hate the Pinkertons?
不知道  一个那么顽强的组织
Beats me, a stalwart organisation like that.
在宾夕法尼亚你帮助运送矿工  让他们送死么？
Did you help send them miners up the fucking scaffold in Pennsylvania?
我在密西西比州工作
I was busy on the Mississip'.
没有希望
Past hope.
没有善良和关心
Past kindness or consideration.
没有正义
Past justice.
没有满足
Past satisfaction.
没有冷暖舒适
Past warmth or cold or comfort.
没有爱
Past love.
也没有惊喜
But past surprise?
会变成一个无尽的多么无趣的人生啊
What an endlessly unfolding tedium life would then become.
不  多丽丝
No, Doris...
我们必须让你经历惊讶
we must not let you be past surprise.
凯莉打盹呢  我去叫醒她
Carrie's napping. I'll awaken her.
不必了  我现在想要这个年轻的姑娘陪我
You needn't. I'd like to see this young lady just now.
好的  多丽丝？
All right. Doris?
Ah  老师在我的记忆力
Ah, teachers one remembers.
总是那么善良
The thrilling kindness of the extra moment taken...
总是那么的鼓舞人心
the extra word of encouragement offered.
可能会这样 “你  小伙子”或者“小姑娘”
"You, young man," or "woman" as the case might have been...
有着令人瞩目的才情
"have an interesting turn of mind."
是的  来回来去总是那些情形
Yes. And to take that extra moment in turn.
Oh 斯托克斯夫人  一句话改变人的一生的
Oh, Miss Stokes, to alter a life's course with a word...
我是多么的尊敬您啊
how I revere you...
还有你的专业水准
your profession.
Well  谢谢  梅利克先生
Well, thank you, Mr Merrick.
不  应该谢谢你  斯托克斯夫人
No, thank you, Miss Stokes.
以及所有如你这般的老师
And all teachers in you.
在你前面的是布洛克的房子
There before you is the Bullock house.
它是最近由布洛克先生建的
It was recently constructed by Mr Bullock.
这些街道啊
These streets.
我要见他  吴
I got to meet him, Wu.
混蛋
Cocksucker!
旧金山混蛋
San Francisco cocksucker.
我要见他
I have got to meet him.
斯维尔根  旧金山混蛋
Swearengen, San Francisco cocksucker meet!
旧金山混蛋和斯维尔根要见面
San Francisco cocksucker and Swearengen got to meet.
吴 我要见他  我看看他有多少料
I've got to meet him, Wu. I've got to see how much juice he's got.
犹太人？
Jews?
Yeah  我要见他 探探旧金山混蛋的底细
Yeah, I've got to see how much juice San Francisco cocksucker's got.
犹太人？犹太人？
Jew? Jew?
-不 吴 不是犹太人  -犹太人？
-No. No, Wu. No Jews. -Jew?
不是犹太人  忘了这个词吧
No Jew. Forget juice.
-忘了它  -不是犹太人？
-Forget juice. -No Jew?
忘了这个词
Forget juice.
不是  斯维尔根  不是旧金山混蛋  也不是犹太人
No, Swearengen. No San Francisco cocksucker. No Jew.
斯维尔根和吴
Swearengen, Wu.
吴和斯维尔根
Wu and Swearengen.
其他的姑娘在哪？
Where are the other girls?
在店里闲逛  怎么了？
Mooning over a dress at that store. What is it?
他和多丽丝在房间里
He's in a room with Doris.
沃尔科特
Wolcott.
-为什么和多丽丝在一起？  -我不知道
-Why is he with Doris? -I don't know.
-Well 为什么不是凯莉？ -凯莉在打盹
-Well, why ain't he with Carrie? -Carrie's napping.
我无法想象
I can't imagine...
关于多丽丝  凯莉告诉沃尔科特什么了
what Carrie might have told Wolcott about Doris...
才让他想干她
to make him want to fuck her.
也许是她报告给赛・托利维了
Maybe that she reports to Cy Tolliver?
好让沃尔科特别把她当球往墙上扔
To keep Wolcott from bouncing Doris off more walls?
从你的杂志上抬头吧  麦蒂
Look up from your fucking magazine, Maddie.
我现在要凯莉
I would like to see Carrie now.
帮我想想  绅士们
Assist me in a flight of fancy, gentlemen.
Well T先生 不要让我想象里昂穿裙子的情景
Well, don't make me think of Leon in a dress, Mr T.
或者我代替他做除了穿衣服
Or me of him anything but fully clothed.
想像梅里克出现在你们面前
Mr Merrick appears before you.
他说  有人砸了我的报社
"Somebody's fucked with my newspaper office," he says.
我的印刷设备一片狼藉
"My presses are a mess.
‘我的字母盘打翻了’诸如此类的情形
"My vowel trays are overturned," or the like.
-你们怎么回答？  -滚蛋
-How do you respond? -Go fuck yourself.
我们不知道这事儿
We don't know anything about it.
如果你当时不在那儿被打了或被杀了
If you ain't here to fuck or be fleeced,
就该谢天谢地了
get on your merry way.
不错  这样怎么样
Good. Now, how about:
在拳击赛中裁判是中立的  梅里克
"Referee's the only neutral in a prize fight, Merrick...
可惜你不是裁判
"and you ain't one of those."
我们可以那么说
We could say that.
我们在说什么？
What would we mean?
我不知道  伙计们  我什么都不知道
I don't know, fellas. I do not fucking know.
Well  你要是不知道  那我们也不知道
Well, if you don't, we don't have to, either.
我在说 在我看来
I am saying, far as I'm concerned...
你们的主动性和主导的能力
your initiative and leadership abilities...
持之以恒的就是不断地问问题
and stick-fucking-to-it-iveness are all in fucking question.
如果我是你们或者其中之一
And was I either or both of you...
我会认为这是个考验
I'd consider this a fucking test.
你感觉他什么时候会露面
When do you suppose he'll show up?
里昂  一旦我们造访了他的地盘之后
Once we've paid a visit to his place, Leon.
Oh
Oh.
以及后果  当梅里克碰上我们
And aftermath, when Merrick's path crosses ours...
他会听到‘中立’和‘拳击赛’
he'll hear of the "neutral" and the "prize fight."
毋庸置疑
In no uncertain terms.
知道了预言的出处
And know the import of that fucking parable.
那么好吧
All right then.
用锤子？
Got any sledgehammers?
必须的
Always.
-我要进去  -不 你不能
-I'm going in there. -No, you aren't.
他不是那种喜欢双飞的人
He ain't the type to be with two women.
我没研究过他的历史
I never took his full history.
我是说他不是
I'm saying he ain't.
凯莉 我们要在这做什么呢？
What are we to do here, Carrie?
除掉她
Get rid of her.
他们会妨害你
They'll let you.
我猜是的  但是并不能解决问题
I suppose they will, but that won't dispose of the problem.
问题是什么？
What's the problem?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不能说
I can't say.
我不想让你看到我
I don't want you to have seen me.
我不在乎你杀了她  她肯定对你做了什么
I don't care you killed her. She must have done something to you.
我是说事情不一样了
I mean something different.
我不想被看到
I don't want to have been seen.
你他妈疯了
Then you're fucking crazy.
你要在这个鬼地方杀了我
And you're going to kill me in this fucking shithole.
你知道怎样能让它无害么？
Do you know how to make it not hurt?
现在我可以断臂保军了
Now, I could cut off my arm.
我要进去
I'm going in.
你的枪不在那儿
Your gun isn't there.
我拿了
I've got it.
继续走  出去
Go on, get out!
斯塔布斯小姐
Miss Stubbs.
乌特先生
Mr Utter.
你做了什么  W先生
What did you do, Mr W?
昂贵的事儿
Something very expensive.
10万美元
$100,000.
现在
For now.
我想用它度过我活着的时间
And more when I want it for as many years as I live.
度过余生[这句话没翻译好]
For all the years of my life.
你明白么？
Do you understand?
我的地方有麻烦了 塞
There's trouble at my place, Cy.
当需要的的时候治安官布洛克又在哪呢？
Where is Sheriff Bullock when he's needed?
她最后向你汇报了  多丽丝提到被打了么？
Her last report to you, did Doris speak of getting beat on?
-搞出的麻烦是哪个人啊 -别跟着我
-That's the man making the trouble. -Don't you fucking follow me.
杰克  你有多少钱？
How much money you got, Jack?
别让我为难  乔安妮
Don't put me in the fucking middle, Joanie.
是的  我不会让你为难的
No, I wouldn't.
1400美元
$1,400.
莱拉  你能去找下乌特先生么
Can you run to Mr Utter, Lila,
让他准备一辆马车
tell him to ready a wagon.
好的  乔安妮
Sure, Joanie.
去拿钱  杰克
Go get your fucking money, Jack.
再拿一袋
Again.
给他打开袋子 确认这是黄金
Open the fucking bag for him, verify it's fucking gold.
我知道但我不想要
I know. I don't want it.
不管怎样  见到你很高兴
Anyways, good meeting you.
出来吧  吴
Come on out, Wu.
底细？
Juice?
如果2万元都不能引他反水  那么你对了
If $20,000 don't tempt him to converse, you're fucking-a-right.
也许你和我应该一起对付他
Maybe you and me should be working for him.
吴  斯维尔根
Wu, Swearengen.
好的  吴  难熬的一天啊
All right, Wu, it's been a long fucking day.
-没有旧金山的混蛋  -拜托  吴  AI累了
-No San Francisco cocksucker. -Come on, Wu, Al's tired.
-赫斯特  -他是个怎么样的人呢
-Hearst. -What about him?
旧金山
San Francisco.
你认为赫斯特和中国佬联合了？
You think Hearst and the Chink's connected?
你以为他生来就能不屑2万美金么
You think he was born looking down his nose at $20,000?
主要事实是  没有存活的目击者
Chief fact is, no witnesses are extant.
我出来的时候另一个女的在这  乔安妮・斯塔布斯
The other madam was here once when I came out, Joanie Stubbs.
-在你杀人之前？  -是的
-Before you did this? -Yes.
当我最后出来的时候  她跑了
When I came back out, she was gone.
-她不在卧室么？  -不在
-Was she ever in the bedroom? -No.
别关心那个女的了
Don't worry about the other madam.
回旅店  吃点东西  如果你还能吃得下话
Go to the hotel. Eat, if you can stand the food.
这里会被处理好的
This will all be took care of.
沃尔科特先生  我告诉过你 我不会坑队友
I told you, Mr Wolcott, all's I can't provide is the cliff.
走吧  离开这
Go on now, get out of here.
对于我提及崔克茜并辱骂了她 我表示抱歉
I apologise for bringing Trixie into it, and calling her what I did.
这话我听过
That wasn't new information to me.
在咱俩谈过之后  我出去找傻逼史蒂夫了
After you and me talked, I searched that idiot Steve out...
骂了他 还打了那个傻逼的脸
to rebuke him and smack him in the face for being who he was.
治安官
Sheriff.
告诉我有关你和盖勒特夫人会面的事
Tell me about your meeting with Mrs Garret.
她一次都没提你的名字
She never once mentioned your name.
她想成立银行以便将营地变得更好
She wants to form the bank to better the camp.
-邀请你了加入了？  -我当执行官
-And asked you to be involved? -To serve as chief officer.
你会很称职的
You'd be a good one.
我感觉她可能有孩子了
I got the impression that she might be with child.
洛特在任何情况下也不会做出那样的饭的
Lot, before God, could make no case for that food.
可能是洛特的妻子做的饭
Lot's wife may have been in that food.
盐放多了
Over salted as it was.
我就这么理解你的意思了
I took that to be your meaning.
我擦
Shit.
别动  该死的
Stay still, God damn it.
在我干你的腿的时候
While I come on your fucking leg.
你很幸运我没干你
You're lucky I'm not fucking you.
你要告诉治安官
You tell the Sheriff how that fucking felt...
我干你的腿的时候你感觉如何
me coming on your fucking leg.
以及我把你从被干屁股救了出来
Or that I saved you from an ass fucking.
在学校你学了什么  他们就教了你这个？
What else did you learn at that school that teached you that?
托利维先生  我的办公室被砸了
Mr Tolliver, my office has been torn apart.
-运气不好啊  -我的出版社被砸坏了
-Hard luck. -My press has been damaged...
我的字母盘无法修复了  还有刚到的教师…
my vowel tray beyond repair. And the newly-arrived schoolteacher...
斯托克斯夫人  被吓得跑回了她的旅馆房间
Miss Stokes, has been badly frightened and has retreated to her hotel.
我们归罪于捣乱分子么？
Do we blame unsavoury elements?
我将此事件作为
I regard this incident as postscript...
特派员访问的增刊
to the visit by County Commissioner Jarry.
有意思
Interesting.
报复我拒绝将杨克顿的债券所有权
Retribution for my refusal to associate my newspaper...
的通知印在报纸上
with Yankton's notice on title to the claims.
你是说在墙上订个通知？
For pinning the notice, you mean, on a wall...
而不是印在报头？
instead of printing it under your masthead?
那就是我的意思
That is my meaning exactly.
朽木先锋报和我干的事无关
Disassociating the Deadwood Pioneer from what I took to be...
与宣告的事正好相反
the opposite of an effort to inform.
也许你要是做好了你的份内  这潭水会平静点
Maybe if you had done your part, calmed the fucking waters a little...
就不会逼着特派员跑
instead of treeing the county commissioner...
民众也会稳当地离开  该干嘛干嘛
the hooples would have gone and got their loads on...
然后等着你的下一期报纸
and been waiting for your next edition.
不  我们见解不同  托利维先生
No, we differ, Mr Tolliver,
对于出版社的作用
on the function of the press.
梅里克  对于你 这不是个教训么？
Ain't the lesson for you in this, Merrick...
被砸坏的机器  报社一点都不能工作了
that with fucked up machinery, the press cannot function at all?
先生 这就是你破坏他人财物的目的？
And is that the vandalism's purpose, sir?
找条狗在我办公室撒野？
And of the dog defecating in my office...
通过你派遣的暴徒来给我教训？
with ruffians dispatched by you as the lesson's author?
对他们是否带狗我表示怀疑
I doubt they had a dog with them.
霍斯泰特勒  你在搞什么？
Hostetler, what the hell are you doing?
-他在这干马  -我没干马
-He was in here fucking a horse. -I did not fuck that horse.
我在问你在干什么？
I'm asking you what you're doing.
我要去拿个修蹄工具
I'm gonna go get a shoeing tool...
然后我要在这儿打死这个混蛋
and I'm gonna hit this bastard right here...
最后像片牛肉一样扔了他
and I'm gonna drop him like a piece of beef.
我没伤害过你
I never fucking harmed you.
我猜他不是在对我说
Guess he ain't talking to me.
我没像他捆着要杀我这样杀你
I didn't kill you like he's fixing to kill me.
你要死了  史蒂夫
You need to die, Steve.
你是这么干你也会付出代价
Hard as you worked, as much shit as you had to eat...
杀了他有意义么
only way it makes any sense to kill him...
如果你要写点东西  你得先听明白我说的
is if you sign everything you got across to me first.
因为我能看到合理性
'Cause then I could see the logic.
我要杀了他  然后我再回来杀了你
I'm gonna kill him, then I'm fucking gonna come back and kill you.
这不是我的想法
And this isn't my will.
你相信上帝会通过一个黑人来显灵么
Do you believe that God can act through a nigger?
上帝不想你被杀
God does not want you to kill.
你相信上帝会让我宽恕你么
Do you believe that God would let me feel mercy toward you...
你给我涂沥青  还干了他的马
that tarred me and fucked his horse?
我信  但我没干马
I do. But I did not fuck the horse.
你会满怀感激的走出去么？
Would you go hence in gratitude...
如果你在这个马厩得到宽恕
if you received mercy in this stable?
我会的
I would.
写下
Write out...
’我干了治安官的马‘  我们让他签字
"l fucked the Sheriff's horse." Then we gonna have him sign it.
-我没干马 -‘我干了’
-I didn't fuck the horse. -"l fucked--"
我自慰的  我在它的腿上
I jerked off. I came on his leg.
你会在这个有点夸大的记录上签字
Would you sign off on that slight exaggeration...
好保住你的脑袋不会被打碎么？
to keep from getting your fucking head smashed in?
是的
Yes.
你会为有色人种祝福
Would you bless coloured folk
承认上帝是我们所有人的圣父么？
and God that's father to us all?
我会的  然后满怀感激的走出去
I would and go hence in gratitude.
-现在走吧  史蒂夫  -走吧
-Go hence now, Steve, go on. -Now go.
如果你的感激消退了 就想想我们有你的签名
And if your gratitude ebbs, remember, we got your signature.
我要走了  我会记住的
I'll go, and I'll remember.
我喝了点酒就睡着了
I took a drink of liquor and it put me to sleep.
他怎么进来的  我都不知道
How he got in, how I got beside myself....
我有17年
I ain't took a drink...
没喝酒了
in 1 7 years.
Yeah Well  你解决这事了
Yeah, well, you're over that now.
我再也不喝了
I don't want any.
那个假小子给你的消息？
That tomboy get you that message?
我欠你的  当他们像以前那样来找你的时候
I owe you. When they come for you like they did before...
你本可以像我做的那样做的
you would have did like I did.
就是快了点 没来得及
Only quicker.
-我很感谢那个消息
-I appreciated the message. -So be it henceforth.
今天过的不好么？
Was it a difficult day?
不
No.
妈妈见了新的教师  并且很喜欢她
Mamma met the new schoolteacher and very much liked her.
梅里克先生领来的
Mr Merrick brought her to call.
好的
Good.
我很喜欢她  我很高兴她最后到了
I liked her very much. I'm delighted she's finally arrived.
不错
Good.
我精力不足
I lack my accustomed stamina.
妈逼的 医生  他们一波一波的来拜见AI
Bullshit, Doc. They've been coming at Al in waves...
他坚持到他们所有人离开
and he stood them all the fuck off.
他已经让谢尔曼人汗颜了
He'd have stopped Sherman shy of the sea.
没用腿  会成为他们关注的借口么？
Without the use of a leg, would they have fired me from a fucking cannon?
Well  我发现你情绪不错
Well, I find you in excellent fettle.
相对于我之前的惨样？
Relative to my former wreckage?
相对而言  是的 Ai的情形是相对的
Relatively speaking, yes. All conditions are fucking relative.
那现在怎么样？
So how is this?
-相对而言？  -比早上好
-Relatively speaking?  -Better than this morning.
好的  谢谢
All right, thanks.
医生  走之前爽爽么？
Poke a girl before you go, Doc?
Well  轮流检查检查她们的阴部吧
Well, change off rummaging their twats.
我希望你没和新到的中国妓女联系
I hope you ain't connected with them new Chinese prostitutes.
我没有  但我正在尝试和她们的皮条客做朋友
I ain't. But I did try to make friends with their pimp.
Yeah
Yeah.
-我们需要支援  －本地的？
-We need to muscle up. -Local?
-不知道能带来谁  -Well  派我去夏延吧
-Don't know who's been bought. -Well, send me to Cheyenne.
你去  我想留你在身边
You go. I want you close.
我想我要出去看看
I think I'll take a look outside.
那个树林大盗怎么样
What about that forest fucking type...
就是你过去在见到我之前一起抢劫的那个
you used to maraud with before you met me?
Crop Ear?
Yeah  他少个号角
Yeah, he lacked the use of a fucking horn.
用不上他了
He ain't available.
Yeah  我最近没听说过他  丹
Yeah, didn't I hear lately, Dan...
Crop Ear去别处抢劫了
Crop Ear's been marauding elsewheres?
Yep
Yep.
别让我们跟三胞胎似的一起出现
Let's not appear as fucking triplets, huh?
从后面下去  你们俩
Go back down, both of you.
还要拖着一部分体重[半身不遂]
Took some fucking portion of the relative fucking weight.
来  来
Come on, come on.
谁伸出个手
Someone put a hand out.
-谁拿到了 -Enid.
-Who got it?  -Enid.
-分成三份 Enid. -谢谢  乔安妮
-Split it three ways, Enid.  -Thanks, Joanie.
-非常感谢  -应该的
-Thank you very much. -Certainly.
那是1400美元  分三份  别回来了
It's $1,400. Split it three ways. Never come back!